

# Michael Powell

- Melbourne, VIC 3000 4 +61488440874
- michael powell1989@hotmail.com
- https://michaelpowell89.github.io/portfolio/

## PROFESSIONAL () **SUMMARY**

Enthusiastic Game/Technical Designer thoroughly experienced at converting ideas to prototypes in Unreal Engine using C++ and Unreal blueprints. A driven Game Developer with experience from three AAA game titles and three mobile applications. Poised and committed in carefully analyzing critiques and requests, incorporating feedback and boosting player engagement.

#### SKILLS

Technical Skills | C++, HTML, CSS, Java, React Blender, Adobe Photoshop, Adobe Illustrator, Adobe XD, Atlassian Jira | Confluence

Soft Skills | Communication, Collaboration, Problem-Solving, Critical-Software Proficiency | Unreal Engine, Thinking, Research and Analysis, Agile Methodology

#### WORK HISTORY

#### **WEB DEVELOPER**

06/2020 to CURRENT

## **Freelance**

- Designed and coded three websites using Adobe Creative Suite, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, jQuery, and React.
- Planned website development and converted mockups into functional web interfaces by utilizing HTML, JavaScript, and JSON coding for creating usable web presence.
- Managed full-cycle design tasks, from conception in Adobe XD and Illustrator to completion in React.

## **QA ENGINEER**

09/2021 to 07/2023

## Centr | Melbourne, VIC

- Collaborated with cross-functional teams to optimize product roadmap through product design, review, implementation, and release.
- Assisted in backlog refinement for both mobile and web platforms, while personally resolving web tasks using React and NextJS.
- Engaged in quarterly hackathons where I was able to design and implement functional prototypes for future enhancements which included playable VR experience in Centr app.
- Fostered culture of cross-functional teamwork, emphasizing test-driven development and striving for enhanced user experience while reducing customer churn.

## **QA ENGINEER / GAME DESIGNER**

09/2018 to 09/2021

## Wicked Witch | Melbourne, VIC

- Collaborated with development team and community to research and information gathering to troubleshoot and improve gameplay and player satisfaction.
- Designed, prototyped and presented potential game mechanics for future game title.
- Provided ongoing research and documentation with relevant competitive titles to design future game mechanics and enhance playability and user engagement.

#### **EDUCATION**

Graduate Diploma | Psychology

11/2015

University of Melbourne, Melbourne, VIC

Bachelor of Arts | Game Design

11/2011

Qantm College, Melbourne, VIC

**REFERENCES** 

Available on request